Abdifatah Farah Jama

Flat 7 Monica Shaw Court, Purchese Street NW1 1EY Abdifatah.jama@icloud.com | (+44) 07563157418|

EDUCATION

QUEENMARY UNIVERSITY OF LONDON | BEng Chemical Engineering (Completed 1st Year) Sep. 2019 – Present

- First Year Result: **69.7%[Average grade for year]**, Relevant Courses: Math's & Computing for Engineers 1 & 2(Avg:70%), Thermodynamic(87.9%)
- Second Year Result: 64%[Average grade for year], Relevant Courses: Control system analysis and design(74.8%), Mass transfer and separation processes(77.2%), Heat transfer and fluid mechanics(67%), Integrated chemical engineering design(64.9%)
- Activities: ISOC Society, Somali Society.

London Academy of Excellence | A Levels | Tottenham, London Sept. 2017 - Jun. July 2019

- A-Levels: ABB in Mathematics, Biology and Chemistry, respectively.
- Activities: Creative Writing Society, Debating society, Football, Basketball.

Park View Secondary School |GCSE |Wood Green, London | 2012-2017.

- GCSE: 10 A*-B including Mathematics(A/8), English Language(A/7), English Literature(A/8)
- Achieved the top 20 results within my year group
- Activities: Joined the Chess Club where I learned a new skill/game

About Me

I am an ambitious 20-year-old that is currently enrolled at a top russell group studying chemical engineering in my third and final year with the intention to join an internship program after my time at university ends. Additionally, over the last year I have found a new hobby in programming specifically using Python. As I still classify myself as a rookie programmer, I still have tons to learn to eventually turn this hobby into something more serious. In the meantime, I have a few small projects hosted on my personal GitHub which include a small automation script that tracks if a gaming console is in stock and purchases if this is the case, with the use of the request library, proxies and selenium library. I believe the ability of teaching my self a skill that I am foreign to shows that I can be thrown into unfamiliar situations but still be able to adapt and learn quickly to a competent level where I can hold my own.

JOB EXPERIENCES

Over the years I have worked typical working-class jobs that I believe allows me to stand out from many candidates as I understand the real world and realities of life.

Warehouse Stock Picker King's Cross St. Pancras Station

Jun 2021-Present

- Picking the stock and packing ready for loading onto the trains sent all around the country.
- Work involves working in chill / freezer rooms.
- Job requires early morning jobs/late night jobs that requires commitment.

Customer Assistant| Westminster, London

Jun 2017- June 2020

- Giving information and helping to solve customer problems.
- Selling products and taking orders
- Fill promotion ends and merchandising units as well as ensuring that the aisles are tidy and clear

PROJECTS AND SKILLS

Low Carbon Ammonia Production Project: Produced a Lab report that focused on producing a low
carbon ammonia production plant in line with the current push to change global proceeses to be more
environmentally friendly.

- Water Expansion Column Project: Produced a Lab report investigating the water softening(removal of calcium carbonate) using an expansion column that can then be sent into mainstream domestic water pipes
- Water Level Control: Project for control system analysis investigating water level control using open and closed loop control with an industry level PID
- Python: Currently learning python in my own time. I have done a few small projects using python such a tictactoe game using numPy, an ecommerce bot that simulates a user clicking on a product and filling out all the necessary information in the checkout menu using selenium. I have also learnt and used matplotlib and pandas library to analyze and display data. Presently, I am looking through object orientated documentation as python is an OOP language by nature. In the long term it is my view to move away from procedural programming to make any code I do produce to be as concise as possible. Wish me luck. (17/08/21). I have know used OOP programming in two small projects that have been uploaded onto github. One being a stock and shares script that day trades 5 stocks at a time using API's. Another project is using OOP to create a bot that purchases a PS5 as soon as stock is available.
- GitHub Link https://github.com/AbdifatahJama

ACTIVITIES/LEADERSHIP

QMUL Chemical Engineering Society

Oct. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Other Interests: Automation, Finance, Consultancy, Investment Banking, Analyst, Basketball, Football, Music.

AWARDS

- London Academy Excellence Tottenham: Attained Top 50 A Level Results out of a year group of 170 students.
- JP Morgan Engineering Virtual Internship Completion Award
- Bright Network Technology Internship